<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>USA - The New Vibes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/usa/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 14:10:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Call For Applications: The Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program</title>
		<link>/2023/05/30/call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program</link>
					<comments>/2023/05/30/call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/?noamp=mobile#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Anim Darko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring Now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GHANA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scholarship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>  The Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program has opened its annual call for applications for the academic year 2023–2024, and the Public Affairs Division of U.S. Mission Ghana is delighted to make the announcement. A Fulbright exchange, the Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program develops leadership skills among foreign professionals who work together to address regional...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/05/30/call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/">Call For Applications: The Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program</a> first appeared on <a href="">The New Vibes</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_wordpress" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/wordpress?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="WordPress" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&#038;title=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" data-a2a-url="/2023/05/30/call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/" data-a2a-title="Call For Applications: The Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program"></a></p><p><span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">The Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program has opened its annual call for applications for the academic year 2023–2024, and the Public Affairs Division of U.S. Mission Ghana is delighted to make the announcement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">A Fulbright exchange, the Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program develops leadership skills among foreign professionals who work together to address regional and global issues and promote change for the benefit of all. This expanding international network exchanges best practices and develops expertise in key areas for cooperation, such as law and human rights, public health, including infectious diseases, climate change, and public policy, through academic study and professional development with U.S. counterparts. The program lays the groundwork for long-lasting, fruitful relationships between Americans and their professional counterparts in other nations, such as Ghana, by giving aspiring leaders and decision-makers experience in American higher education, society, culture, and professional organizations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">The Humphrey Fellowship is a mid-career, non-degree program for professionals interested in developing their leadership skills and learning more about their professional fields of study, unlike the typical Fulbright and most other foreign scholarship programs. The Humphrey Program also places a strong emphasis on the sharing of information and understanding regarding topics that are relevant to both the United States and the countries of the Fellows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;" href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjAC6o5FBgRpZo4o4d4HwTLDyhLE5sKV95bP6ViijseoKmBQY-AA2QT72X1N2s8c-jVxZi6u8y9ZJqR84oOB0CWfoHWtqads7g8Ohb_QYJq6uU99aalPfNA5xrU6dGgKkT9vpN8qSq4ivOamsL63Zer6bXTGI2VH6OUVv3QLuu29hsYCZw81joc9za2Tw/s642/exchange%20program.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjAC6o5FBgRpZo4o4d4HwTLDyhLE5sKV95bP6ViijseoKmBQY-AA2QT72X1N2s8c-jVxZi6u8y9ZJqR84oOB0CWfoHWtqads7g8Ohb_QYJq6uU99aalPfNA5xrU6dGgKkT9vpN8qSq4ivOamsL63Zer6bXTGI2VH6OUVv3QLuu29hsYCZw81joc9za2Tw/w546-h345/exchange%20program.jpg" width="546" height="345" border="0" data-original-height="440" data-original-width="642" /></a></span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS:</span></h2>
<h3 style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; color: #333333; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px 0px 26px; padding: 0px; text-align: left; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Applicants should:</span></h3>
<ol style="text-align: left;">
<li><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: inherit;">Presently live in Ghana as a citizen or permanent resident (Please note: Ghanaian nationals with dual citizenship from the U.S. are not eligible for the program).</span></li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="color: #333333; font-family: inherit;">Have a bachelor&#8217;s degree from college.</span></li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="color: #333333; font-family: inherit;">Have a minimum of five years of full-time work experience in the appropriate field (prior to August 2023) and a keen interest in the policy implications of their area of expertise.</span></li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="color: #333333; font-family: inherit;">Have demonstrated leadership skills and a track record of civic engagement.</span></li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="color: #333333; font-family: inherit;">Have the possibility of getting a study leave from the applicant&#8217;s company is high.</span></li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="color: #333333; font-family: inherit;">Have a commitment to public service, whether in the public or private sector, that has been demonstrated.</span></li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="color: #333333; font-family: inherit;">Be in good health. A Medical History and Examination Report will be required of successful candidates.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="background-color: white;">Also, In order to conduct their research projects and effectively work with their colleagues in a U.S. university, applicants should be fluent in English. (Note: TOEFL examinations are necessary &#8211; check below for additional details).</span><br />
</span></p>
<div>
<div></div>
<div><b>Important:</b> English language proficiency and the TOEFL Test</div>
<div></div>
<div>The TOEFL test will be mandatory for all Humphrey finalists (Test of English as a Foreign Language). Only the finalists who have been contacted will have the examination fee covered by the program. Once a candidate has been selected as a finalist, they are next needed to sit the exam. Before, during, and after the application process, all applicants are urged to prepare for the TOEFL exam. For this program, TOEFL scores of 80 or higher are regarded as competitive. Visit the Education USA Center or <a href="https://gh.usembassy.gov/education-culture/educationusa-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>online</i></b></a> for available study aids and materials.</div>
<div></div>
<div>English language instruction is given to nominees with lower TOEFL scores in an effort to engage with candidates from non-elite communities, rural areas, minority groups, and other groups who may be good candidates but lack the essential language abilities. Before the Humphrey Fellowship academic year begins, candidates may be required to participate in an English training program in the United States to prepare Fellows.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Qualities Required From A Competitive Candidate</h2>
<div>
<ol style="text-align: left;">
<li>Strong motivation and serious commitment to finishing the course of study and returning to Ghana to put knowledge to use at one&#8217;s native institution or other in-country institutions applications that are professionally written.</li>
<li>Candidates with little or no prior experience in the United States are given preference.</li>
<li>Candidates who have never before been awarded a Fulbright scholar grant will be given preference.</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div>Applications are encouraged from those in underrepresented groups. This includes applicants who are women, from underprivileged and underrepresented demographics, have little prior exposure to international affairs, are minorities, have impairments, or are otherwise disadvantaged. appropriate accommodations may be requested by people with. Please send an email to <a href="mailto:accraExchange@state.gov">accraExchange@state.gov</a> with the subject line <b><i>&#8220;Request for Reasonable Accommodation &#8211; HHF 2024.&#8221;</i></b></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Other grounds for ineligibility</h2>
<div>Recent grads from undergraduate universities (even if they have significant positions)</div>
<div>academic researchers or university instructors without managerial responsibility</div>
<div></div>
<div>Those who have spent at least one academic year in a graduate program in the United States during the seven years before August 2024.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Individuals with dual U.S. citizenship or U.S. permanent resident status may not apply to the program as they are ineligible for a J visa. Individuals with in-country experience in the U.S. of any kind lasting longer than six months during the five years prior to August 2024 are also prohibited from applying.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">WHAT TO AIM FOR</h2>
<div></div>
<div>Fellows are assigned to university campuses for the duration of the academic year where they pursue unique program objectives and collaborate closely with their Humphrey colleagues in workshops and seminars. Aside from attending seminars and conferences, fellows are also expected to fulfill a six-week professional affiliation requirement. They are also expected to participate in professional development activities off the campus of their university.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Many universities organize fellows into professional disciplines. Since there are nearly as many different nationalities represented in current Humphrey cohorts as there are Fellows, in addition to learning about American culture, Fellows must also take into account the traditions and customs of other cultures. Someone who can adjust, be flexible and tolerate diversity is needed for this.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">COMPONENTS OF PROGRAM</h2>
<div>Academic Study Without a Degree: Humphrey Fellows pursue specialized study programs at affiliated host universities, where the lack of degree requirements allows each Fellow the option to follow a self-directed, unique program at a host university. Following a competitive selection procedure, roughly 13 campuses in the United States were chosen based on their capacity to provide institutional and professional resources to host cohorts of Fellows in specific fields of study. Humphrey Fellows cannot ask to be placed at a certain university. At least one designated faculty coordinator for academic and administrative support is present on each site. Faculty advisors also help Fellows pursue well-balanced academic and professional programs. (Note: Humphrey Fellows are not permitted to switch during their program from non-degree to degree status.)</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Leadership and Professional Development: Professional visits, skill-enhancement seminars, conferences, training courses, and professional affiliation are some examples of professional enrichment activities (placement). The professional affiliation offers full-time, first-hand exposure to a U.S. workplace for a minimum of six weeks. By providing a global perspective to issues in their respective disciplines, these professional affiliations enable Fellows to actively contribute to American communities while strengthening their relationships with American colleagues. Each Fellow creates, early in the academic year with the help of the local campus coordinator and faculty advisors, a comprehensive schedule of practical professional activities tailored to the Fellow&#8217;s program goals.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">AREAS OF STUDIES</h2>
<div>The objectives of Mission Ghana and the following study areas are in line with US foreign policy. All applications will be taken into consideration by the U.S. Embassy, but those in the following areas are especially encouraged:</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h3 style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px 0px 26px; padding: 0px; text-align: left; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: bold; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Human and Institutional Capacity:</span></h3>
<ul style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; list-style-image: initial; list-style-position: initial; margin: 0px 0px 23px; overflow: auto; padding: 0px 0px 0px 40px; vertical-align: baseline;">
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Economic Development</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Finance &amp; Banking</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Public Policy Analysis and Public Administration</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Technology Policy and Management</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px 0px 26px; padding: 0px; text-align: left; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: bold; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Rights and Freedoms:</span></h3>
<ul style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; list-style-image: initial; list-style-position: initial; margin: 0px 0px 23px; overflow: auto; padding: 0px 0px 0px 40px; vertical-align: baseline;">
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Communications and Journalism</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Law and Human Rights</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px 0px 26px; padding: 0px; text-align: left; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: bold; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Sustainable Lands:</span></h3>
<ul style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; list-style-image: initial; list-style-position: initial; margin: 0px 0px 23px; overflow: auto; padding: 0px 0px 0px 40px; vertical-align: baseline;">
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Agricultural and Rural Development</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Natural Resources, Environmental Policy, and Climate Change</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Urban and Regional Planning</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px 0px 26px; padding: 0px; text-align: left; vertical-align: baseline;"><span style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: bold; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Thriving Communities:</span></h3>
<ul style="background-color: white; border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; font-stretch: inherit; font-variant-alternates: inherit; font-variant-east-asian: inherit; font-variant-numeric: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; line-height: inherit; list-style-image: initial; list-style-position: initial; margin: 0px 0px 23px; overflow: auto; padding: 0px 0px 0px 40px; vertical-align: baseline;">
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Public Health Policy and Management</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Substance Abuse Education, Treatment, and Prevention.</li>
<li style="border: 0px; box-sizing: border-box; font-feature-settings: inherit; font-kerning: inherit; font-optical-sizing: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-stretch: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-variation-settings: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Educational Administration, Planning, and Policy</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">TERMS AND CONDITIONS</h2>
</div>
<div>International travel, tuition, and university fees, accident and illness insurance, monthly maintenance coverage, and funding for books and professional activities, are all included in the Humphrey Fellowship. The accompanying dependents are not financially supported by the Humphrey Program.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">APPLICATION &amp; INSTRUCTIONS</h2>
<div>
<div>Use this website to access the application and instructions: <a href="https://apply.iie.org/huberthhumphrey"><b><i>https://apply.iie.org/huberthhumphrey</i></b></a></div>
<div></div>
<div>To apply, users must first log in, provide their email address, and then set a password. This password will be required throughout the application process, so please keep it handy. Also, applicants are urged to read the guidelines before submitting their forms. For spelling and punctuation errors, pay close attention. Don&#8217;t copy from others. Except when entering acronyms, avoid using capital letters (or &#8220;ALL CAPS&#8221;) when completing the application or the required essays.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Objectives and the Program Plan</h3>
<div>The outlined goals have to be in line with the broad objectives of the Humphrey Fellowship Program. This program is not intended for those who want to finish their degrees or do research in conventional academic fields. Your goals and strategy should show a sincere desire to expand, widen, and improve your capacity to professionally contribute to Ghana&#8217;s growth. Your personal statements, program plan, and career objectives must all be explicit, well-thought-out, and clear.</div>
<div></div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Letters Of Recommendation</h3>
<div>Each nominee needs two letters of recommendation. The existing employer of the nominee should provide one of the letters.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Certificates and transcripts</h3>
<div>For each higher education degree obtained, we require a course schedule, grades or scores, and proof that the degree was awarded.</div>
<div></div>
<div><b>WARNING:</b> Before uploading your application to the online form, draft it first in a word document. Keep in mind that your application serves as an <b><i>&#8220;interview on paper.&#8221;</i></b></div>
<div></div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Further Advice for a Good Application:</h3>
<div>
<ol style="text-align: left;">
<li>Employ simple, direct words and express yourself clearly.</li>
<li>Explain how your goals and interests align with the prevailing issues and trends in Ghana and how you plan to use your experience when you get back.</li>
<li>Proofread your work and request that others review and comment on your application (grammar and spelling mistakes will reflect poorly)</li>
<li>Avoid Plagiarizing</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Plagiarism Guidelines</h3>
<div>Use of another person&#8217;s thoughts, words, or research without giving due credit to the original author constitutes plagiarism. You must use one of the following citation formats when using the works, research, or even your own published works of others: Chicago, APA, or MLA style.</div>
<div></div>
<div><b><i>DEADLINE FOR APPLICATIONS: June 1, 2023.</i></b> Use this website to access the application and instructions: <a href="https://apply.iie.org/huberthhumphrey">https://apply.iie.org/huberthhumphrey</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>Only candidates who have been shortlisted will be called for an interview. You can resubmit your application and try again the following year if you don&#8217;t hear anything about your initial submission.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><b>__________________________________________</b></div>
<div><b>TAGS:</b></div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><b><a href="https://gh.usembassy.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">US EMBASSY IN GHANA </a>    <a href="https://gh.usembassy.gov/education-culture/exchange-programs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EXCHANGE PROGRAMS</a>    <a href="https://gh.usembassy.gov/education-culture/exchange-programs/the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HUBERT H. HUMPHREY</a></b></div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><a href="https://gh.usembassy.gov/education-culture/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>EDUCATION &amp; CULTURE</b></a></div>
</div>
<div>
<div><b>__________________________________________</b></div>
<div><b> </b></div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_wordpress" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/wordpress?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="WordPress" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&amp;linkname=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=%2F2023%2F05%2F30%2Fcall-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program%2F&#038;title=Call%20For%20Applications%3A%20The%20Hubert%20H.%20Humphrey%20Fellowship%20Program" data-a2a-url="/2023/05/30/call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/" data-a2a-title="Call For Applications: The Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program"></a></p><p>The post <a href="/2023/05/30/call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/">Call For Applications: The Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program</a> first appeared on <a href="">The New Vibes</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/05/30/call-for-applications-the-hubert-h-humphrey-fellowship-program/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
