<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Migraine Archives - The Health Vibes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/migraine/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/migraine/</link>
	<description>Your Health Is Your Choice</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 14:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Migraine And Mental Health: Causes, Effects On Health, Symptoms &#038; Treatment</title>
		<link>/2023/05/25/migraine-and-mental-health-causes-effects-on-health-symptoms-treatment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Anim Darko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 03:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Migraine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/wordpress/2023/05/25/migraine-and-mental-health-causes-effects-on-health-symptoms-treatment/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Migraines can significantly impact mental health, causing negative effects on overall well-being. Learn about the causes, symptoms, and treatment options available to manage migraines and their effects on mental health.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/05/25/migraine-and-mental-health-causes-effects-on-health-symptoms-treatment/">Migraine And Mental Health: Causes, Effects On Health, Symptoms &#038; Treatment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">The Health Vibes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">In this article, we will discuss what Migraine is, its effects on Mental Health, symptoms, causes, and treatment as explained by <a href="https://web.facebook.com/samuel.archimedes" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>the Medical Health Professional and Team Lead of Healthy Choice, Mr. Samuel Ntiamoah</i></b></a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">Migraine, known by far as the neurological condition that <a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/headache/migraine-headaches" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>causes recurrent episodes of severe headaches</i></b></a> are typically <a href="https://www.ninds.nih.gov/health-information/disorders/migraine" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>pulsating or throbbing in nature</i></b></a>, and is often<br />
accompanied by other <a href="https://www.health.harvard.edu/a_to_z/migraine-a-to-z" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>symptoms such as nausea, vomiting</i></b></a>, and<a href="https://medlineplus.gov/migraine.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <b><i>sensitivity to light and sound</i></b></a><b><i>.</i></b> Migraines are more than just headaches and can last anywhere from <i>&#8220;a few hours to several days&#8221;, and affect millions of people worldwide</i>. <span style="font-size: 11pt;"><b><i><a href="https://www.forbes.com/health/body/migraine-relief-at-home/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">According to the 2019 Global Burden of Disease (GBD) Study, migraines are the second greatest cause of disability worldwide.</a> </i></b></span>The exact cause of migraines is not fully understood, but it is thought to involve changes in the brain and nervous system. There are various triggers for migraines, including stress, certain<br />
foods, hormonal changes, and changes in sleep patterns. Treatment for migraines can include medications to relieve symptoms and prevent future episodes, as well as lifestyle changes such as reducing stress, getting enough sleep, and avoiding triggers.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.istockphoto.com/photo/shot-of-a-young-woman-suffering-from-a-headache-gm1276385699-375914521?phrase=Migraine+and+mental+health" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-4495 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/migraine-2.png" alt="" width="731" height="499" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Types Of Migraine</span></h2>
<div>
<h3><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://www.everydayhealth.com/migraine/guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Migraine With Aura</a></span></h3>
<p style="font-size: medium; font-weight: 400;">
<p style="font-size: medium; font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">A migraine with aura is a type of migraine headache that is characterized by a specific set of symptoms that occur before or during the headache. The aura symptoms can include visual disturbances such as flashing lights, blind spots, or zigzag lines, as well as sensory symptoms like tingling or numbness in the face or hands. Other symptoms that may occur during a migraine with aura include difficulty speaking, confusion, and weakness on one side of the body. These symptoms typically last for 20-60 minutes and are followed by the headache phase of the migraine. Migraine with aura is thought to be caused by changes in the brain that lead to the activation of the trigeminal nerve, which is responsible for pain perception in the head and face.</span></p>
<h3><a href="https://www.everydayhealth.com/migraine/guide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Migraine Without Aura</a></h3>
<p>A migraine without aura is a type of migraine headache that does not involve the specific set of symptoms known as aura. Instead, the headache typically begins as a moderate to severebbing pain that is often felt on one side of the head. Other common symptoms of migraine without aura may include sensitivity to light, sound, or smell, nausea, and vomiting. These symptoms can last for several hours to several days and can be debilitating for the individual experiencing them. Migraine without aura is thought to be caused by changes in the brain that lead to the activation of pain pathways and the release of inflammatory substances that cause headache pain. It is a common type of migraine, affecting approximately 70-90% of people who experience migraines.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://migrainetrust.org/understand-migraine/types-of-migraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Abdominal Migraine</a></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">Abdominal migraine is a type of migraine headache that is characterized by recurrent episodes of stomach pain, nausea, and vomiting in the absence of a gastrointestinal disorder. Unlike typical migraines, abdominal migraines do not usually involve head pain as a symptom. This condition is more common in children and typically occurs in those under the age of 10. The episodes of abdominal migraine can last from a few hours up to several days and can be triggered by various factors such as stress, certain foods, and changes in sleep patterns. It is important for parents to be aware of the symptoms of abdominal migraine and to seek medical attention if they suspect that their child may be experiencing this condition. Treatment for abdominal migraine may include medications to relieve symptoms and prevent future episodes, as well as lifestyle changes such as avoiding trigger foods and getting enough sleep. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://migrainetrust.org/understand-migraine/types-of-migraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Menstrual migraine</a></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">Menstrual migraine is a type of migraine headache that occurs in women and is linked to the menstrual cycle. It typically occurs in the days leading up to menstruation or during menstruation. Women who experience menstrual migraines may also experience other symptoms such as nausea, vomiting, and sensitivity to light and sound. Hormonal changes are thought to be a trigger for migraines, and women who experience them may find that they occur more frequently during times of hormonal fluctuations, such as during puberty, pregnancy, or menopause. Treatment for menstrual migraine may include medications to relieve symptoms and prevent future episodes, as well as lifestyle changes such as stress reduction, regular exercise, and avoiding trigger foods. Some women may find that hormonal treatments, such as birth control pills or hormone replacement therapy, can help reduce the frequency and severity of menstrual migraines. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://migrainetrust.org/understand-migraine/types-of-migraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hemiplegic migraine</a></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">A hemiplegic migraine is a rare form of migraine that is accompanied by weakness on one side of the body, which is known as hemiplegia. This weakness is a form of migraine aura and occurs with other typical migraine aurae signs like changes in vision, speech, or sensation. The symptoms of hemiplegic migraine are similar to those of a stroke and can be quite severe. There are two types of hemiplegic migraine: familial hemiplegic migraine, which runs in families, and sporadic hemiplegic migraine, which occurs in individuals with no family history. If a person experiences weakness with their headache, they should seek immediate medical attention and not make assumptions about their condition. Treatment for hemiplegic migraine may include medications to relieve symptoms and prevent future episodes. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://migrainetrust.org/understand-migraine/types-of-migraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vestibular migraine</a></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">Vestibular migraine is a type of migraine that is characterized by episodes of dizziness or vertigo and is often accompanied by other migraine symptoms such as headache, nausea, and sensitivity to light and sound. Vestibular migraines are caused by a problem in the nervous system and are more common in people who have a history of migraines. The symptoms of vestibular migraine can include a sensation of spinning or movement, feeling off-balance or unsteady, and difficulty concentrating. Treatment for vestibular migraine may include medications to relieve symptoms and prevent future episodes, as well as lifestyle changes such as reducing stress and avoiding triggers. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3258393/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Episodic migraine</a></h3>
<p>Episodic migraine is a type of migraine headache that is characterized by having headaches on fewer than 15 days per month. This is in contrast to chronic migraine, which is characterized by headaches on 15 or more days per month for three or more months. Episodic migraine can be triggered by various factors such as stress, certain foods, and changes in sleep patterns. The symptoms of episodic migraine can include a throbbing or pulsing headache, sensitivity to light and sound, and nausea or vomiting. Treatment for episodic migraine may include medications to relieve symptoms and prevent future episodes, as well as lifestyle changes such as stress reduction and avoiding trigger foods.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://migrainetrust.org/understand-migraine/types-of-migraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chronic Migraine</a></span></h3>
<p><span style="line-height: 107%;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Chronic migraine is a type of migraine headache that is characterized by the experience of migrainous headaches on at least 15 days per month for at least three months. Chronic migraine is different from<br />
episodic migraine, which is characterized by having fewer than 15 headache days per month. Chronic migraine can be extremely debilitating and can have a significant impact on a person&#8217;s quality of life, leading to missed work or social engagements. Treatment for chronic migraine may include medications to prevent headaches, as well as lifestyle changes such as stress reduction, regular exercise, and avoiding trigger foods. It&#8217;s important to work with a healthcare provider to develop an appropriate treatment plan for chronic migraine, as the condition can be complex and multifaceted. </span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">It is important to note that not all individuals with migraines will experience these specific types, and some individuals may experience a combination of different these types.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span></p>
</div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/basics/migraine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stages Of Migraine</a></span></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Prodrome</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">This stage can occur hours or days before the headache and includes symptoms such as fatigue, mood changes, and food cravings.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Aura</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">Not all migraine sufferers experience this stage, but those who do may experience visual disturbances such as seeing flashing lights, zigzag lines, or blind spots. Other symptoms may include numbness or tingling in the face or hands, difficulty speaking, or confusion.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Headache</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">This stage is what most people associate with migraine. The headache is usually severe and can last anywhere from a few hours to a few days. It is often accompanied by other symptoms such as nausea, vomiting, and sensitivity to light and sound.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Postdrome</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">This stage occurs after the headache has subsided and includes symptoms such as fatigue, confusion, and mood changes. Some people may feel euphoric or extremely tired during this stage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Causes Of Migraine</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">The exact cause of migraines is not fully understood, but it is thought to involve changes in the brain and nervous system. According to the <a href="https://americanmigrainefoundation.org/resource-library/what-causes-migraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>American Migraine Foundation</i></b></a>, migraines are likely caused by a combination of genetic, environmental, and lifestyle factors. Some common triggers of migraines include<br />
hormonal changes, foods and drinks (such as chocolate, alcohol, and caffeine), stress, changes in sleep patterns, and certain medications. Additionally, changes in weather, bright lights, and strong smells can also trigger migraines for some people. It&#8217;s important to note that not all triggers are the same for<br />
everyone, and some people may not have any obvious triggers at all.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />
<a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/migraine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Symptoms Of Migraine</a></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">The symptoms of migraines can vary from person to person, but some common symptoms<br />
include:</span></p>
<ol style="text-align: left;">
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Intense, throbbing headache – usually on one side of the head</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Nausea and vomiting</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Sensitivity to light, sound, and smells</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Blurred vision or disturbances, such as seeing flashing lights or zigzag lines</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Dizziness or vertigo</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Tingling or numbness in the face or extremities</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Difficulty speaking or finding words</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;">Fatigue or weakness</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/headache-disorders" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>Migraine symptoms can last anywhere from a few hours to several days</i></b></a> and may be preceded<br />
by warning signs, such as mood changes, food cravings, or changes in energy levels. It is essential to note that not everyone who experiences migraines will have all of these symptoms, and some people may experience additional symptoms not listed here.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.istockphoto.com/photo/side-view-of-emotionally-stressed-mid-adult-woman-standing-in-the-kitchen-next-to-a-gm1321004522-407368858?phrase=Migraine+and+mental+health" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-4493 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/migraine.png" alt="" width="671" height="457" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />
</span><span style="font-family: inherit;">How Migraines Affect Mental Health</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">As emphasized by the <a href="https://americanmigrainefoundation.org/migraine-101/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i>American Migraine Foundation</i></b></a>, individuals who experience migraines are more likely to experience anxiety and depression than those who do not. Migraines can be extremely debilitating and can interfere with daily activities, leading to feelings of frustration, helplessness, and hopelessness. The pain and discomfort associated with migraines can also disrupt sleep patterns, which can further exacerbate feelings of anxiety and depression. Additionally, the fear of experiencing another migraine attack can cause anxiety and stress, which can, in turn, trigger more migraines. Therefore, it is<br />
important for individuals with migraines to seek appropriate treatment not only for the physical symptoms but also for their mental health. Some of the means by which migraines affect health are:</span></p>
<ol style="margin-top: 0in;" start="1" type="1">
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Anxiety and depression: </b>People with migraines are more likely to experience anxiety and depression than those without migraines. The pain and disruption caused by migraines can lead to feelings of hopelessness, frustration, and isolation, which can contribute to the development of anxiety and depression.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Impaired cognitive function: </b>Migraines can also impair cognitive function, including memory, attention, and concentration. This can make it difficult to perform daily tasks and can lead to feelings of frustration and decreased self-esteem.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Sleep disturbances: </b>Migraines can disrupt sleep patterns, leading to insomnia or poor-quality<br />
sleep. This can exacerbate feelings of anxiety and depression and make it more difficult to manage migraine symptoms.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Social isolation:</b> Migraines can be unpredictable and debilitating, which can make it difficult to<br />
maintain social relationships. This can lead to feelings of loneliness and social isolation, which can contribute to the development of anxiety and depression.</span></li>
</ol>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Treatment Of Migraine</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">Migraines can be treated using various approaches, including:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">1. <b>Acute medications:</b> These medications are taken when a migraine attack occurs to treat<br />
the symptoms. Examples include triptans, such as sumatriptan, and gepants, such as ubrogepant and rimegepant.</span><span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">2. <b>Preventive medications:</b> These medications are taken to prevent migraine attacks and are recommended for individuals who experience frequent or severe migraines. Examples include beta-blockers, antidepressants, and anticonvulsants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">3. <b>Anti-nausea medications:</b> When a migraine attack is associated with nausea or vomiting, an antiemetic can be used to help relieve these symptoms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">4. <b>Lifestyle changes:</b> Certain lifestyle changes, such as managing stress, getting enough sleep, and avoiding triggers, can also help reduce the frequency and severity of migraines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">It is important to work with a healthcare or medical professional to determine the most appropriate<br />
treatment plan for your individual needs.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.istockphoto.com/photo/doctor-explain-brain-model-gm1406509035-458030495?phrase=Migraine+and+mental+health" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-4494 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/treatment.png" alt="" width="747" height="398" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">How Mental Health Can Be Improved For People With Migraines</span></h2>
<ol style="margin-top: 0in;" start="1" type="1">
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Seek treatment:</b> If you experience migraines, it is important to seek treatment from a healthcare or medical professional. This can help manage symptoms and reduce the risk of developing anxiety and depression.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Practice self-care: </b>Self-care activities such as exercise, meditation, and relaxation techniques can help reduce stress and improve mental health.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Build a support network: </b>Building a support network of friends, family, and healthcare or medical professionals can help reduce feelings of isolation and improve mental health.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>Manage triggers:</b> Identifying and managing triggers such as stress, lack of sleep, and certain foods can help reduce the frequency and severity of migraines, which can improve mental health.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">In conclusion, migraines can have a significant impact on mental health, including anxiety, depression, impaired cognitive function, sleep disturbances, and social isolation. Seeking treatment, practicing self-care, building a support network, and managing triggers can help improve the mental health of people with migraines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;">Take good care of yourself and Make a choice to stay healthy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>_______________________________________________________</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>TAGS:</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b><a href="https://web.facebook.com/samuel.archimedes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SAMUEL NTIAMOAH</a>     <a href="https://web.facebook.com/healthychoice101" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HEALTHY CHOICE</a>     <a href="https://www.forbes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FORBES</a>     <a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JOHNS HOPKINS MEDICINE</a>  </b></span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://www.health.harvard.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HARVARD HEALTH</a>     <a href="https://medlineplus.gov/migraine.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MEDLINEPLUS</a>     <a href="https://www.ninds.nih.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NIH</a>     <a href="https://www.healthline.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HEALTHLINE</a>     <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PSYCHOLOGY TODAY</a>  </span></b></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://www.who.int/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WHO</a>     <a href="https://www.everydayhealth.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EVERYDAY HEALTH</a>     <a href="https://migrainetrust.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">THE MIGRAINE TRUST</a> </span></b></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NATIONAL LIBRARY OF MEDICINE</a>     <a href="https://americanmigrainefoundation.org/resource-library/what-causes-migraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMERICAN MIGRAINE FOUNDATION</a></span></b></p>
<p><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>________________________________________________________</b></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/05/25/migraine-and-mental-health-causes-effects-on-health-symptoms-treatment/">Migraine And Mental Health: Causes, Effects On Health, Symptoms &#038; Treatment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">The Health Vibes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
